Guide to the Lorna D. (Lorna Dysart) Smith Papers, 1930-1981 (inclusive), 1965-1975 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
Lorna D. (Lorna Dysart) Smith Papers,
1930-1981 (inclusive), 1965-1975 (bulk)
Special Collections M0194
Smith, Lorna D. (Lorna Dysart), 1897-1981.
1.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Lorna Dysart Smith, 1970-1974.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lorna Dysart Smith was born in Centralia, Washington, 1897. She worked as a student nurse and as a researcher for novelist Theodore Dreiser (1938-1945), but is noted as a civil rights and social reform worker. She died in San Jose, California, January 11, 1981.
SCOPE AND CONTENT NOTE
This collection consists chiefly of letters written to Lorna Smith from authors and politicians with whom she regularly corresponded. Also included are several typescripts and articles by and about her. Much of the correspondence concerns Upton Sinclair, and authors Erna Holyer and Theodore Dreiser are also represented. Correspondence by and from other authors and politicians may also be found in the collection.
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE, CA. 1928-1979
  - INCOMING, CA.1928-1979
    - Albrecht, Alfred-Aronson, James, 1947-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barclay, Julius and Gertrude-Belfrage, Cedric, 1963-1977, and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Belfrage, Grace-Church for President Committee, 1951-1976, and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clark, Dick-Edwards, Don, 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Edwards, Don-Gregellas, F. 1963-1979, and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hahn, Bob-Hayes, Janet Grey (Mayor of San Jose), 1965-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Holyer, Erna-Hubbard, Elbert, 1966-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jahnshen, Anette-Lockwood, Phyllis, 1948-1977, and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - McAlister, Alister-Norris, Kathleen, ca. 1928-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Osterby, Marian-PHP Institute, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - PHP INstitute-Rudd, Hughes, 1965-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Scully, Alice-Scully, Frank, 1945-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sinclair, David-Sinclair, Upton, 1930-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sould family-Swanberg, W.A., 1948-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Takashima-Zomer, 1930-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - OUTGOING, 1965-1979
    - Allatt, Edward-Editors, Mercury News, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Holyer, Erna, 1971-1977, and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hopkins, Jeanette-Special Collections, Stanford University Libraries, and unknown, 1965-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)